

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211





Muthu Subramanian B 👩 Featured



Sr. Project Manager-Associate Engineering Manager seeking roles in Solution Architecture, Program Management, Project Management, Delivery Management, Agile Methodology, Process Improvement, Risk Analysis, Data Analysis, Change Management, JIRA, GIT, Rally, AWS



Total Experience: 14 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: BCA[Computers]

Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Designation: Sr. Project Manager - Associate

Engineering Manager

Current Company: Photon Infotech

Current Location: Chennai

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore.Chennai

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance Role: Program Mgr

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Sr. Project Manager-Associate Engineering Manager, Program Manager, Solution Architecture, Program Management, Project Management, Delivery Management, Agille Methodology, Process Improvement, Risk Analysis, Data

Analysis, Change Management, JIRA, GIT, Rally, AWS

Verified: Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

 $\textbf{Exhibited leadership in implementing Agile methodology to add value to the deliverables; working with consultants in a substant of the deliverables and the deliverables are the deliverables. \\$ identifying process improvements in deliverables; developing methods to achieve delivery of desired results Expertise in guiding and Managing a large team of professionals for implementing Agile projects in Digital (Web & Apps) and in ERP sharing experience with a project team and providing feedback & advice to new Agile project teams Excellent track record of designing customized IT solutions for high profile clients; capability to interface with clients, suggest viable solutions, cultivate relations with them for securing repeat business Domain expertise entails Banking, Manufacturing, Retail, and Travel & Tourism History of excelling in introducing new organizational change & driving innovation, integrating new technologies & quality initiatives in the project to facilitate business excellence.

Work Experience

Photon Infotech as Sr. Project Manager -Associate Engineering Manager Jan 2020 to Till Date

Key Result Areas: Working as an Agile Program management professional, with responsibilities including Stakeholder management in being the Zone IT Lead, and handling multiple brands for Asia-Pacific zone, and also having responsibilities as a Brand manager in IT maintenance in SiteCore CMS for a boutique brand supporting 12 countries in Asia-Pacific region, and delivering enhancements the agile way in less than 2 week intervals. Supervising and mentoring other Agile projects, along with Agile Product Owner, Scrum Master and Delivery Management teams. Planning & organizing Scrum meetings, facilitating sprint planning & review meetings, sprint retrospective meetings, sprint backlog, story estimation, daily stand-ups, iteration & release planning and reviews Managing all phases of the project life cycle inclusive of scoping, development, integration, deployment, testing, maintenance and production support Additional responsibilities include working on maintenance revenue management for the fixed bid projects for the same brand. Providing Agile Consulting and coaching to delivery teams; working as Agile Coaches Lead and Support to Agile Coaches by providing consultation, removing blockers & impediments for Agile adoption Supporting standards, processes & procedures necessary to produce the deliverable from the PMO team. Monitoring team's adherence to Agile process during project execution, identifying issues & assisting team to resolve the same Maintaining healthy relations with internal & external stakeholders to provide support for various issues; keeping a close track of developments in the field of IT applications and updating the Senior management as appropriately.

VThink Global Technologies Private Limited as Scrum Master/Agile Coach - Project Manager (Hybrid)

Jan 2019 to Nov 2019

Key Result Areas: Providing Agile Consulting and coaching to delivery teams; working as Agile Coaches Lead and Support to Agile Coaches by providing consultation, removing blockers & impediments for Agile adoption Acting as liaison between stakeholders and Technical Teams to define functionality in both current and future state applications using Agile/ Scrum methodology Coordinating with Solution Architect and Development Team to ensure optimal product design delivery & alignment across domains Supervising Agile projects, along with Agile Product Owner,

Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Scrum waster and Delivery wanagement hybrid Providing training to the team on the Agrie process; ensuring training will continue all the time during the project execution and continuous improvement on velocity, quality, processes Monitoring teams' adherence to Agile process during project execution, identifying issues & assisting team to resolve the same Focusing on people and continuous improvement; providing team a platform for improvement not only during the retrospective but all the time; creating safe environment for healthy conflict and meaningful collaboration Frontleading delivery of projects from the stage of initiation till monitoring & control including planning, estimation & scheduling, integrating change control, planning risk responses and contingency planning Planning & organizing Scrum meetings, facilitating sprint planning & review meetings, sprint tertospective meetings, sprint blanning & review meetings, sprint blanning & review meetings, sprint blanning & review meetings, sprint blanding sprint blanning and reviews Identifying documents related to components and maintaining detailed study of the same as per the product changes, by getting in touch with the product developers Facilitating resource allocation & setting up communication channels across various horizons of the organization structure Managing all phases of the project life cycle inclusive of scoping, development, integration, deployment, testing, maintenance and production support Interacting with customers to work on new product ideas, and end user requirements; ensuring healthy relationships with customer organizations as well as with internal customers Conceptualizing & implementing technology-based solutions for enhancing functional efficiency, achieving business excellence, managing risks and planning for contingencies to ensure minimal effect on deliverables Maintaining healthy relations with internal & external stakeholders to provide support for various issues; keeping a close track of developments in the field of IT applications and updating top management about the same Reviewing existing systems & business requirements and facilitating the implementation of new systems/ processes in line with the business goal and objectives Supporting standards, processes & procedures necessary to produce the deliverable from the PMO

Tata Consultancy Services as Assistant Consultant Jul 2014 to Jan 2019

Key Result Areas: Acted as SAP Offshore Delivery Lead; ensured proper communication of the project, process and business analysis information to all the stakeholders using document analysis, interviews, brainstorming, lessons learned, reviews and workshops Used various technological tools such as SAP HCM, JIRA, MS Office Assisted team to come up with 'Definition of Done' and Epic Scope definitions Worked as Delivery Manager on US Payroll incidents and changes for Olympus; managed delivery of incidents on US Payroll and US Benefits for SCE, like issues in payroll runtime errors, disability issues in benefits Managed SAP HCM Services and incident support & change management for enhancements in a multi-vendor SAP support environment Acted as Incident Management Lead in Southem California Edison and managed the delivery on timesheet to finance & month end reconciliation issues Supervised delivery of finance posting, 3rd party postings, garnishments, pay revisions, step increase related issues Spearheaded incident management of Target Canada in SAP HCM Services and incident support & TCS SPOC for multivendor SAP support environment; worked on Integrated Environment with tools like CIF, MFT, AXWAY, Vertex Worked as Development Lead on Nokia Project managing the OMPA modules in Nokia

CSC India Pvt. Ltd as SAP HCM Functional Lead Mar 2007 to Jul 2014

Growth Path: SAP HCMFunctional Lead - Jul'11 to Jul'14 Resource Manager - Mar'07 to Dec'10

Key Result Areas: As SAP HCM Functional Lead: Acted as Production Support Lead (Incident Management)- US Benefits and Payroll Projects undertaken: Benefits Customisations: Configuration includes aspects of plan design including benefit area, assigning currency to those benefit areas, benefit plan types (Health & Dental Plan), plan attributes, benefits providers, dependant coverage grouping ESS/MSS: Configured the headers, areas, sub-areas, services; assigned the country specific services, configured portal menu, created IMEW, roles and work sets, defined types of leave for processing and created rule group, maintained feature like IVMID, WEBMO, LDAYW, assigned workflow to each absence type Objects: Worked on gathering requirements for PA Act 32 (Pennsylvania State Tax Act) report generation and COBRA (Consolidated Omnibus Benefits Reconciliation Act) plan changes to vendors (SHPS and ADP)

As Resource Manager: Spearheaded internal resource mobilisation against open positions; acted as SPOC for any resources (internal/external) on-boarded to customer Liaised with stakeholders to identify employee release across verticals to bridge the demand supply gap Supervised demand - supply bench management for Technology Consumer Goods vertical with 200+ active customers

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: BCA (Computers) from Alagappa University in 2010

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:
Diploma in Information Technology
Professional Scrum Master 1
Certified Agile Coach
Certified Scrum Master
SAP Certified Application Associate
Certified SAFe Consultant
Certified Solutions Architect
Prince2 Foundation (Persuing Practitioner)

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Chill Manage	Vencies Leat lead	Emerican
Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
Jira, Rally		
Git Hub, JIRA		0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
MS Project, MS office		
KANBAN		
SAP HCM		

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
english				
Hindi				
Telugu				
Tamil				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: **General**Physically Challenged: **No**

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.